ROGELIO PEDRAZA

FULL-STACK SOFTWARE ENGINEER

CONTACT

+1 (832) 332-4333



lovecore@pm.me



linkedin.com/in/rogeliop98 in



EDUCATION

ASSOCIATE OF APPLIED SCIENCE

Lone Star College, Cypress, TX 2016 - Present

WEB DEVELOPMENT CERT.

Rice University Coding Bootcamp, Houston, TX 2022

KEY SKILLS

Agile Development

Quality Assurance

UX/UI

Writing & Editing

Browser-Based Technologies HTML, CSS, JavaScript (ES6), Cookies, Local Storage

> Deployment Heroku, Git, GitHub Pages

Databases MySQL, GraphQL, REST API, MongoDB

> Libraries & Frameworks React, ¡Query, Node.is, Express, Bootstrap, TailwindCSS

SUMMARY

Part-time student and coder with 6+ years' experience in retail and sales who recently entered the software engineering career field. Built multiple MERN stack web applications using the latest web development technologies. Familiar with agile development in terms of daily scrum, writing tests, user stories and acceptance criteria, and minimum viable product.

EXPERIENCE

SECURITY PROFESSIONAL

Allied Universal / NW Houston, TX / 09/2020 - Present

An American provider of security products and services, including access control, intrusion, alarm detection, and IP-based video systems; janitorial; transition planning; green cleaning; and staffing services

- Secured sites and reported all significant activity on various sites
- Assisted employees, coworkers, and customers with directions, site operations, or special event instructions
- Ensured a safe environment and crime deterrence by remaining visible and attentive to surroundings

REPRESENTATIVE

Sprint / Cypress, TX / 03/2018 - 12/2018

An American telecommunications company that offered wireless voice, messaging, and broadband services through its various subsidiaries

- Exceeded daily/weekly sales goal by \$2k \$4k consistently by being knowledgeable in products and promotions
- Ensured smooth workflow by efficiently performing essential business operations such as inventory, logistics, sales data input, and cash flow

SALES ASSOCIATE

Nautica / Cypress, TX / 11/2014 - 04/2017

An American apparel brand of primarily men's, women's, children's apparel and accessories, as well as home, watches, and fragrance

- Assisted customers with all in-store needs.
- Performed daily business operations and functions
- Ensured daily business goals were met by being knowledgeable in current products, promotions, and assisting new team members with best sales practices

ROGELIO PEDRAZA

FULL-STACK SOFTWARE ENGINEER

EXPERTISE

Visual Studio Code

Insomnia

Git Bash

Figma

Microsoft Office

Windows/macOS

PROJECTS

TWEEZER

A functional clone of the social media app Twitter

HABITUAL

An app that allows users to track their daily habits in a visually simplified display to improve daily motivation, productivity, and overall mental well-being

INTERESTS

Visual Arts

Gyms & Health Clubs

Cooking

Video Games

Music

Horticulture & Gardening

REFERENCES

DANTE MCCLENDON

Supervisor

Sprint, Cypress, TX +1 (832) 496-6430

BRANDIJONES

Supervisor

Allied Universal +1 (337) 739-1163

MICHAEL ADAME

Supervisor

Nautica, Cypress, TX +1 (832) 830-6756